DAN LASH

danlash@gmail.com • (517) 775-2716

SUMMARY

Developing software with a passion since I was 13 years old, my experience spans many platforms, languages, operating systems and work environments. I believe in agile methodologies and pragmatism, and I am always interested in new technologies and techniques.

I am a lifelong learner and teacher and want to work with people that have a similar mentality. I want to build high quality software that not only solves problems but brings joy to people who use it. Team is very important to me as is balance in all things.

SKILLS

JavaScript C# HTML CSS Ruby Python LESS Express Node Mocha Backbone Socket io	PostgreSQL Redis Jenkins SQL Server Visual Studio Git MySQL Rake Salesforce Microsoft CRM Wit Heroku	Web Development Architecture Agile Methodologies Web Services Software Engineering Test Driven Development Integration Object Oriented Design SOA SaaS Entrepreneurship Functional Programming
Socket.io ASP.NET MVC	Heroku IIS	Functional Programming Process Improvement
		•

EXPERIENCE

Leads to Conversations

Co-Founder & CTO

03 / 2014 - Present

Atlanta, GA

Uncovering hidden opportunities in sales data and improving the lead qualification process. Fully integrated and synchronized with Salesforce, we provide analytics to team leaders and productivity tools for sales development representatives.

The server uses a custom designed eventually consistent, bottom-up, distributed worker architecture. The client application utilizes the Flux architecture with Knockout bindings that refresh via a websocket connection. In reporting, we applied functional programming techniques to event streams along with React to render SVG graphs.

VersionOne

Code Whisperer

04 / 2010 - 03 / 2014 Atlanta. GA

Developed project and process management software for teams following an agile process. Our team was experimental, with lots of autonomy, and used leading edge client and server side technologies. Full time pair programming, test driven development, collaborative design and sustainable pace were highly valued. I specialized in implementing JavaScript both on the client and server using Backbone, CoffeeScript, Node and more.

GreenStone Farm Credit Services

03 / 2007 - 04 / 2010

Senior Application Developer

East Lansing, MI

Developed front end replacement and enhancement systems in ASP.NET for a legacy mainframe that supports credit and lending to farmers. Products are based around and fully integrate with Microsoft CRM. The software-as-a-service strategy resulted in a suite of web services that provide value-added access to accounting systems from multiple end points.

Artemis Technologies

05 / 2005 - 11 / 2006

Software Engineer

East Lansing, MI

Collected requirements for highly diverse software projects, designed, developed, tested and deployed solutions. Was the lead of a team of three developers and interacted directly with clients to assure quality.

MATRIX

02 / 2003 - 05 / 2006

Programmer

East Lansing, MI

Used open source web software to help humanities organizations integrate with technology.

EDUCATION

Michigan State University

08 / 2002 - 05 / 2006

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

East Lansing, MI

ASSOCIATIONS

ACM

YMCA

Atlanta CoderDojo

Spartasoft

Lansing .NET Users Group

Indianapolis Python Meetup

HONORS

HHS Computer Science Award '01, '02

MSU Deans List x2

ACM State Competition 2nd '01, 5th '02

YMCA 5 Year Service Award